Masaki Yoshiiwa

Personal Data

Name	Masaki Yoshiiwa
Email	masaki.yoshiiwa@gmail.com
GitHub	github.com/qlawmarq
LinkedIn	linkedin.com/in/qlawmarq

Summary

Front-end developer with extensive experience as full stack developer, with a demonstrated history of working in several industries.

Specialized in web application and mobile application development.

Skilled in React.js, Vue.js, TypeScript, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python, etc.

Also has extensive experience developing from scratch, and has skill to build CI/CD workflow like automated deployment.

Education

Apr 2012 – Mar 2017 Yokohama City University, Japan Bachelor of Arts

Extracurricular Activities

External Projects

- Wrote an article about Visual Studio Code plug-ins for Software Design of June 2021 (Japanese edition only).
- Joined public translation project Gatsby.js documents to Japanese.

Skill

Languages

- Japanese (Native speaker)
- English (Business working proficiency)

Programming Languages

- TypeScript (Expert)
- JavaScript (Expert)
- CSS (Expert)
- HTML (Expert)
- Python (Proficient)
- PHP (Proficient)

Programming Frameworks

- React.js (Expert)
- React Native (Expert)
- Vue.js (Proficient)
- Angular (Proficient)
- FastAPI (Proficient)
- Laravel (Proficient)

Cloud Computing Services

- Amazon Web Services (Intermediate)
- Google Cloud (Intermediate)

CI/CD Tools

• GitHub Actions (Proficient)

Container Engines

- Docker (Proficient)
- Kubernetes (Intermediate)

Monitoring Tools

• Sentry (Intermediate)

Career History

October 2021 - Now: Panthos Cloud Consulting

Job Title	Senior software developer
Employment Type	Full-time
Location	Gold Coast, Queensland, Australia
Website	panthos.com.au
Business Description	Software development, IT consulting
Number of employees	Under 50

Web/Mobile app development for multiple services

- Developed multiple web/mobile app and their api and their CI/CD Workflow, by internal and external request.
- Application Technologies
 - React.js
 - TypeScript
 - Python
 - FastAPI
 - Google Cloud
- · Some examples are described below.

Development of FieldStream app (web/mobile)

- Developed web application and mobile native application (iOS/Android) from scratch.
- Built a CI/CD Workflow with GitHub Actions for automated deployment.
- · Application Technologies
 - TypeScript
 - Python
 - React Native (Expo)
 - Google Cloud
 - Docker

Development of web application platform for ACL group

- Developed multiple web applications from scratch, and maintained and scaled them.
- Setup the application infrastructures with Google Kubernetes Engine (GKE).
- · Application Technologies
 - Python
 - TypeScript
 - FastAPI
 - React.js (Next.js)
 - Google Cloud
 - Docker
 - Kubernetes

October 2020 - October 2021 : Rakuten Mobile, Inc.

Job Title	Front-end developer (Lead)
Employment Type	Full-time
Location	Tokyo, Japan
Website	corp.mobile.rakuten.co.jp/english
Business Description	Telecommunications business and network communications businesses
Number of employees	Over 1000

Front-end development for multiple services (B2C/B2B)

- Front-end development using React.js.
- Responsible for web front-end development.
- In some projects, worked as lead developer.
 - Task management
 - Code Review
 - o Adjust specifications and check implementation
- Built a CI/CD Workflow with GitHub Actions for automated deployment.
- · Application Technologies
 - React.js
 - TypeScript
 - Redux
 - Cypress
 - o HTML5
 - o CSS3
 - Google Cloud

Development of UI components library to be used in the team

- Developed UI component library that can be commonly used by all frontend development team.
- · Application Technologies
 - React.js
 - TypeScript
 - Storybook
 - Cypress
 - o HTML5
 - o CSS3

Managing Akamai CDN service

• Setting and managing Akamai CDN Service for all Rakuten mobile app ecosystem

December 2019 - September 2020 : Photoraction Inc.

Job Title	Web application developer
Employment Type	Full-time
Location	Tokyo, Japan
Website	photoruction.com
Business Description	Software services in the construction sector
Number of employees	Under 100

Development of Photoruction

- Developed some of new features for Photoruction web app, and maintained it.
- Responsible for development of all web-related areas including API server, front-end, DB, infrastructure.
- Application technologies
 - o PHP
 - JavaScript
 - Laravel
 - Vue.js
 - o Amazon Web Services
 - o HTML5
 - o CSS3

Development of Photoruction Eye

- Developed prototype of a web service from scratch.
- Lead on technology selection and architecture design.
- Building a CI/CD environment with GitHub Actions for automated deployment and more.
- · Application technologies
 - TypeScript
 - React.js
 - o Hasura GraphQL Engine
 - PostgreSQL
 - GitHub Actions
 - o Auth0
 - Amazon Web Services
 - o HTML5
 - o CSS3

January 2019 - August 2019 : Kokochie Inc.

Job Title	Web application developer
Employment Type	Full-time
Location	Tokyo, Japan
Website	kokochie.co.jp
Business Description	Software development such as web service and web media
Number of employees	Under 50

Development and maintenance of "Dear" web-based invitation card service for weddings

- Developed and maintained the app features.
- Responsible for development of all web-related areas including API server, front-end, DB, infrastructure.
- Application technologies
 - o PHP
 - JavaScript
 - Vue.js
 - jQuery
 - Laravel
 - Amazon Web Services
 - o HTML5
 - o CSS3
- Achievement
 - Received the Good Design Award 2019 for the website I implemented all design

Commercial web site development

- Developed some of commercial web sites for clients, and maintained it.
- Application technologies
 - o PHP
 - JavaScript
 - Vue.js
 - jQuery
 - Amazon Web Services
- Clients
 - Yoshinoya (Japanese restaurant)
 - The Nippon Foundation Paralympic Support Center

April 2017 - December 2018 : JASTEC Inc.

Job Title	Software developer
Employment Type	Full-time
Location	Tokyo, Japan
Website	www.jastec.co.jp/eng
Business Description	IT software development for various industries
Number of employees	Over 1,000

Worked on several projects, mainly from design to implementation, developing, also testing.

Development of a system for purchasing insurance for a major insurance company in Japan

- Support the development of an application to assist in explaining and applying for insurance products.
- Responsible for development and testing
- Application technologies
 - o C#

Development of a shipping management system for a major shipping company in Japan

- Developed a new app to help track shipping packages
- Responsible for design, development and testing
- · Application technologies
 - o C#
 - JavaScript
 - HTML
 - CSS

Web application development for stock orders for a major securities company in Japan

- Support development of applications for trading stocks and other financial commodities
- Responsible for development and testing
- Application technologies
 - Java
 - JavaScript
 - o HTML5
 - o CSS3